Hyde Park, Boston, Mass. Clarendon Congregational Church records, 1878-1960.
Congregational Library & Archives
Hyde Park, Boston, Mass. Clarendon Congregational Church records, 1878-1960.
RG0102
Congregational Library & Archives
2.18 Cubic Feet
(2 boxes)
Clarendon Congregational Church was located in Hyde Park Boston, Massachusetts. The church was organized in 1880 and dissolved circa 1964. This collection houses administrative records including church records, meeting minutes, and scrapbooks from Clarendon Congregational Church.
Clarendon Congregational Church (Hyde Park, Boston, Mass.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by Francis A. Troy in March 1983 and Elizabeth A Spinello in June 1994; 1994-03.
Historical Note
Clarendon Congregational Church was organized in 1880. Rev. Samuel Dana Hosmer was the first acting pastor from September 1879 to his resignment in April of 1882. Rev. Hosmer graduated from Harvard in 1850 and Andover Newton Theological School in 1856. Clarendon Congregational Church incorporated in 1890. In 1930, the church celebrated its 50th anniversary by unveiling a stained-glass window titled "The Transfiguration". This artwork was inspired by the 12th century windows of the same name that resides in the Cathédrale de Chartres, France. The Clarendon Congregational Church dissolved circa 1964.
Scope and Contents
This collection houses administrative records from the Clarendon Congregational Church in Hyde Park Boston, Massachusetts. The collection includes church records, meeting minutes, church school meeting minutes as well as scrapbooks containing various programs, orders of service, circulars, and photographs.
Arrangement
Materials have been arranged in chronological order by start date.
Church records and registers.; Photograph albums.; Scrapbooks.; Sunday schools.; Worship programs.; Clarendon Congregational Church (Hyde Park, Boston, Mass.)
- Building records, 1878 1912; 1878-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Register, 1880 1960; 1880-1960 (Box 1, Volume 3)
- Programs and circulars, 1885 1929; 1885-1929 (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Pictorial records, 1892 1930; 1892-1930 (Box 2, Volume 1)
- Church records, 1902 1928; 1902-1928 (Box 1, Volume 4)
- Church school records, 1923 1938; 1923-1938 (Box 1, Volume 7)
- Church records, 1928 1937; 1928-1937 (Box 1, Volume 5)
- Programs and circulars, 1929 1935; 1929-1935 (Box 1, Volume 2)
- Pictorial records, 1930 1948; 1930-1948 (Box 2, Volume 2)
- Programs and circulars, 1935 1939; 1935-1939 (Box 2, Volume 4)
- Church records, 1938 1950; 1938-1950 (Box 1, Volume 6)
- Orders of service, 1943 1950; 1943-1950 (Box 1, Volume 8)
- Pictorial records, 1949 1956; 1949-1956 (Box 2, Volume 3)